Guide to the William E. Phillips Papers, 1969-2001
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
William E. Phillips papers 1969-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Phillips, William E., 1930-
0.25 Linear Feet 28 Items
William E. Phillips was an executive and chairman of Ogilvy & Mather and Ogilvy Group advertising agencies.
The William E. Phillips Papers span the years 1969-2001 and include writings, speeches and printed materials that document Phillips' career with Ogilvy & Mather.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William E. Phillips Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Biographical Note
1930 Jan. 7 Born, Chicago, Ill.
1951 B.A., Cornell University
1951-1955 Officer, U.S. Navy
1955 MBA, Northwestern University Brand Manager, Procter & Gamble
1959 Joined Ogilvy & Mather agency
1981-1988 Chairman and CEO, Ogilvy & Mather Worldwide
1988-1989 Chairman, Ogilvy Group Executive Committee
Phillips is also past chairman of Outward Bound's International Board, and has served as director for several firms, including Sunglass Hut and Lillian Vernon.
Collection Overview
The William E. Phillips Papers span the years 1969-2001 and include writings, speeches and printed materials that document Phillips' career with the Ogilvy & Mather advertising agency.
The collection is arranged into two categories of materials: Printed Materials, and Writings and Speeches. Phillips writings and speeches cover a wide range of themes, but he was particularly concerned with improving client-agency relations, agency creativity and productivity, and community involvement.
Related Materials: Related materials pertaining to the Ogilvy & Mather agency may be found in the Edgar Hatcher Papers, the Jock Elliott Papers, the Robert S. Smith Papers, the David B. McCall Papers, and in the J. Walter Thompson Company Advertising Vertical Files.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Phillips, William E., 1930-
Advertising executives
Advertising agencies -- History
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Ogilvy & Mather
Speeches. (AAT)
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Ogilvy & Mather and Ogilvy Group printed materials, 1980-1990, (2 folders)
  Arranged alphabetically, and therein chronologically by date of publication.
  - Annual reports, 1980-1988
  - Staff meeting, 1984
    Includes comments by Phillips, pages 16-19.
  - Viewpoint, 1982-1990
    Publication of Ogilvy & Mather. Phillips wrote articles for several issues.
    - Why Business Must Support the Arts, 1982
    - Why Your Advertising Agency Needs a Better Product, 1986 Sept./Oct.
    - Giving Something Back, 1989 Aug.
- Writings and Speeches 1969-2001, (2 folders)
  - America is a 'Splintering' Market, 1972
  - Better Creativity and Adequate Compensation: The Keys to Advertising Productivity in the '80s, 1982
  - Consumer is Ready! Are You? 1980
  - 'Customer is Always Right', 1982
  - Introduction: Alan Greenspan, undated
  - Jane, Can You Hear Me? 1986
  - Last 50-plus Year--Plus Some Predictions on Commercial Communications and the Importance of Brands, 2001
  - Need for a Youth Service Corps, 1988
  - Principles of Account Management, 1986
  - Sound an Alarm! 1986
    Remarks written by David Ogilvy, read by Phillips, with introduction and comments also by Phillips.
  - Speaking the Same Language Does Not Always Mean Thinking the Same--The Anglo-American Paradox, 1985
  - Strategy is What the Boss Wants to Do, 1979
  - Training: The Heart and Soul of Your Future, 1984
  - Underneath the Iceberg; or, How O&M Grabbed the Hershey Bar, 1969
  - Why Your Advertising Agency Needs a Better Product, 1985
  - You Can't Afford Not to Get the Most Out of Your Agency, 1981